Guide to the Richard Wright Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1933-1977; Series I; 38; (92 boxes)
  - ANTHOLOGIES (Containing works by Wright)
    - Announcements and reviews - clippings
      - Negro Caravan, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - The Negro Novel in America Today, 1958 Dec 21
      - The Negro Since Emancipation, 1965 Apr 17
      - The New Caravan, 1936-37 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - New Challenge, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - O. Henry Memorial Award Prize Stories, 1938-42 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - The Outnumbered, 1968 Feb 25 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Pageant of Ghana, 1958 Sep 3
      - Primer for White Folks, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Second Armchair Companion, 1946 Jul 14
      - Social Insight Through Short Stories, 1946 Oct 13 (Box 4, Folder 64)
      - Soon One Morning, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Story: The Fiction of the Forties, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - A Treasury of Short Stories, 1948 Jan 19
      - Twice A Year [including Stieglitz Memorial Portfolio], 1947-48
      - The World's Best, 1950 Jul 30 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - Young and Black in America, 1970 Dec 20
      - Zero, 1949 Mar 23
  - ARTICLES, ESSAYS AND REPORTS
    - "Alas, My Old Favorite Brooklyn Barbershop," drafts, typescript corrected and carbon (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - "The American Negro," holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - "American Negroes in France"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1951 Apr 24 (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - Printed version, (as "Les Noirs Americaines et la France"), France- Observateur, 1951 May 3
      - Printed version, The Crisis, 1951 Jun-Jul
    - "The American Problem" [It's Negro Phase], drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, [1950s] (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - "A Paris les G.I. Noirs on appris à connaître et à aimer la liberté,"
      - Draft, holograph, [1946] (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Printed version, Samedi-Soir, 1946 May 25
    - "Avant Garde"
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - Clipping announcing contest winners (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "The Barometer Points to Storm," draft, typescript, corrected, [1937] (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Blueprint for Negro Writing," draft, typescript carbon, corrected [with 2 leaves of second carbon and typescript and carbon of transcript prepared by Michel Fabre for publication in 1970], 1937 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "Can the American Negro Survive?," drafts, holograph and typescript (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - [Chicago], draft, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - "Christus lebt im Untergrund," printed version, Vorwärts, 1959 Mar 6 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - "Defense de la Paix," printed version, Vie Libre, 1949 Feb (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "De la Côté de l'Or au Ghana," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - "Derrière l'affaire [McGee]"
      - Draft, typescript carbon, 1951 Jun 4 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Printed version, Droit du Vivre, photocopy, 1951 May 15
    - "The Ethics of Living Jim Crow," excerpt published as "Jim Crows Leveregler" in Kobenhavn Dagbladet Politikens, 1955 Aug 22 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - "Las Fallas: A Pagan Celebration," draft, typescript carbon, corrected [related to Pagan Spain ], [1954-55] (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - [French Images of the American Negro], draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - "French West Africa," draft, typescript and carbon [with notes], [1959 May 12] (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - "The Future of Literary Expression," draft, typescript (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - [George Gershwin], notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - [Greetings from American artists who live in France!], drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - [Haitian Biographies], notes, holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - "Harlem" [is Human], draft, holograph, [1960] (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - "The heart, for reasons that reason does not know, is on both sides...," draft, typescript, corrected (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - "Homage à Quincy Jones," draft, typescript carbon, [1961] (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - "L'homme du Sud," printed version, France Etats-Unis, 1950 Dec
      See: Oversize, Box 199, folder 1923
    - "How Bigger Was Born"
      - "1st draft," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - Working draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 95)
      - "2nd draft," typescript, corrected (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - "3rd draft," [setting typescript, corrected], 1940 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - "4th draft," typescript and carbon, [1940] (Box 5, Folder 98-99)
      - Printed version, Saturday Review of Literature, 1940 Jun 1 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      - Clippings and announcements, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - "How He Did It: And Oh-- Where Were Hitler's Pagan Gods?," printed version, Daily Worker, 1938 Jun 24 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - "How Jim Crow Feels"
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, [1946] (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - Clippings, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      - Printed version (as "Dans le monde entier je sais reconnaître un négre du Sud"), Paris-Matin, 1946 Jun-Jul
        See: Oversize, Box 119, folder 1923
    - "L'humanité est plus grande que l'Amerique ou la Russie"
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, [1948] (Box 5, Folder 105)
      - Printed version, Franc-Tireur, 1948 Dec 16
    - "Hymn to the Sinking Sun," draft, typescript carbon (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - [I am an American, but...], draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - "I Bite the Hand that Feeds Me"
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected [with working notes on advance proof of David L. Cohn's article, "The Negro Novel: Richard Wright"], [1940] (Box 5, Folder 108)
      - Setting typescript, corrected, [1940]
      - Printed version, Atlantic Monthly, 1940 Jun
      - Printed excerpt ("Richard Wright Answers a Lynch Apologist"), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 109)
      - Clippings, 1940
    - "I Choose Exile," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - "If Bigger Wasn't Black and If He Had Money And If They'd Let Him Go to Aviation School, He Could Fly" (excerpt from Native Son ), printed version, P.M. Magazine, 1941 May 7 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - "I Tried to be a Communist"
      - Notes, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 112)
      - Clippings, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 113)
      - Fan mail, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - French translation, Les Temps Modernes, with clippings, 1949 Jul (Box 6, Folder 115)
      - Printed excerpt ("Why I Quit Communism") from The God That Failed, New York Post, 1950 Jul 13 (Box 6, Folder 116)
        See also: Anthologies - The God That Failed, Box 119, folder 1922
    - "Letters from a Sharecropper"
      See: Writings of Others - Unidentified, Box 89, folder 1084
    - "Littérature Noire Americaine"
      - Printed version, Les Temps Modernes, 1948 Aug (Box 6, Folder 117)
      - Clippings, 1948
    - "Memories of My Grandmother," drafts, typescript, corrected [with photocopy for research] (Box 6, Folder 118-119)
    - "Naissance d'un Roman Nègre" [translation of "How Bigger Was Born"?], La Nef, clippings - announcements, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - "Ein Neger zum ersten Male in Afrika," printed version, Die Woche, 1955 Oct (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - "The Negro and the Parkway Community House"
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, [1941] (Box 6, Folder 122)
      - Printed version, pamphlet, 1941
    - "The Negro People March: A Noted Negro Leader Tells of the Part His People Play in Building the Democratic Front," printed version, Sunday Worker (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - [Negro Soldiers], draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - "Note on Jim Crow Blues (Southern Exposure)," draft, typescript, corrected, [1949] (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - "Notes sur les blues," printed version La revue du jazz, 1949 Apr (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - [O'Hara, John, Hell Box (1947)], notes on O'Hara's stories, typescript on notecards, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - [On Literature], drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - [On Writing Autobiography], drafts, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - "A Personal Report from Paris," draft, typescript, corrected, [1948?] (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - "Personalism," draft, typescript, corrected [with notes], [1935-37?] (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - "Personalities in the Arts and Science Greet Earl Browder: The Negro People Understand," printed version, Daily Worker, photocopy, 1940 May 20 (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - "Psychiatry Goes to Harlem" ["Psychiatry Comes to Harlem"]
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, [1946] (Box 6, Folder 133)
        See also: Box 139, folder 2028
      - Printed version, pamphlet, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 133a)
    - "Repeating a Modest Proposal (With Apologies to Old Jonathan)"
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, [ca. 1937?] (Box 6, Folder 134)
      - Galley proof, n.d.
    - "Richard Wright Calls Upon Workers to Aid Peace Fight," printed version, Daily Worker, 1941 Feb 11 (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - "Richard Wright Describes the Birth of Black Boy
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, [1944] (Box 6, Folder 136)
      - Printed version, New York Post, 1944 Nov 30
    - [The Role of the Artist in America], notes (with holograph notes for story on Joe Louis/Max Schmeling fight on verso), [1938] (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - "Roots and Branches," draft, typescript, corrected (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - [Rural Sports], draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Scrapbook of Daily Worker articles, 1937 Jun-Dec
      See: Oversize, Box 123, folder 1969
      Contents: (arranged chronologically)
      - "Negro Writers Launch Literary Quarterly" [byline: Richard Wright], Jun 8
      - "WPA Slashes are Bar to Harlem Homes" [byline: Richard Wright], Jul 8
      - "Young Writers Launch Literary Quarterly, Sept. 1" [byline: Richard Wright from San Antonio Register, Jul 10
      - "Negro Union Painters Seek Higher Wages", Jul 14
      - "Butcher Slugs Negro Youth Asking Change", Jul 14
      - "Negro Actors to Appear at Mother Bloor Fete" [unverified], Jul 15
      - "Protests Against Slugging Grow: Butcher Who Attacked Boy is Fired" [byline: Richard Wright], Jul 15
      - "Bar Negro Relief After Pink Slip Cuts", Jul 20
      - "Store Clerks Demand End of Jim Crow", Jul 20
      - "U.S. Invasion of Puerto Rico to be Protested" [unverified], Jul 22
      - "Women Picket Italy's Consulate Tomorrow", Jul 22
      - "Fla. Lynching Draws Harlem Protest Action" [unverified], Jul 22
      - "100 Negro, White Women Picket Italian Consulate", Jul 23
      - "Pickets Ask Negro Hiring in Movie House" [unverified], Jul 25
      - "A People's Book Store" [unverified], Jul 26
      - "Harlem Party to Protest Japan's Action", Jul 26
      - "Torchlight March Called August 7 by Harlem Group", Jul 26
      - "Harlem Spurs Scottsboro Boys to Fight", Jul 30
      - "Harlem to Hold Peace Parade on Wednesday", Jul 31
      - "Plan Parley on Feudalism in West Indies" [unverified], [Jul]
      - "Got Raw Deal on WPA Says Negro Actor" [unverified], Jul 1
      - "Harlem C.P. to Hear Report by Jack Stendhal", Aug 2
      - "Plenum Report: Stachel to Speak on June Parley Tomorrow at Renaissance Casino" [unverified], Aug 3
      - "Negro, with 3-week-old Baby, Begs Food on Streets" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 4
      - "Harlem Cop Compelled to Apologize for Abuse" [unverified], Aug 8
      - "C.P. Leads Struggle for Freedom, Stachel Says" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 9
      - "Negro Charges Discrimination by AFL Heads", Aug 11
      - "Scottsboro Fight Pushed at Harlem Rally", Aug 11
      - "Communist Head Speaks at Sidewalk University", Aug 12
      - "Huddie Ledbetter, Famous Negro Folk Artist, Sings the Songs of Scottsboro and His People" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 12
      - "Communist Leader Warns on Harlem Tiger Stooges" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 13
      - "Harlem Plans to Send 25 on WPA March", Aug 13
      - "ALP Seeks New Schools for Harlem", Aug 14
      - "Strikers Seek Reduced Rent in Harlem" [unverified], Aug 14
      - "What Happens at a Communist Party Branch Meeting in the Harlem Section?" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 15
      - "Harlem Crowd Shows Feeling on Chiseling", Aug 16
      - "Negro Union to Celebrate Twelfth Year", Aug 16
      - "Negro Group Attacks RR Jim Crow Policy" [unverified], Aug 17
      - "Pullman Porters to Celebrate 12th of Their Union" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 19
      - "Race Tolerance Lecture Scheduled Here on Tuesday", Aug 19
      - "Negro Congress to Convene in Phila.", Aug 21
      - "Record of Nat'l Negro Congress", Aug 21
      - "Scottsboro Boys on Stage is Opposed" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 21
      - "WPA Official Charged with Negro Bias", Aug 23
      - "Low-Cost Rent in Harlem Too High for Many", Aug 23
      - "Harlem Party to Hear Berry on 18th Anniversary", Aug 24
      - "Negro Unions Plan Campaign on Education", Aug 24
      - "'Opportunity for Soviet Youth Unlimited,' Says Negro Musician" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 24
      - "Citizens Ask Committee to Probe Harlem" [unverified], Aug 26
      - "Statement on Scottsboro is Made by Group", Aug 27
      - "Famous Negro Leaders Guide Congress Action", Aug 27
      - "Born A Slave, She Recruits 5 Members for Communist Party" [byline: Richard Wright], Aug 30
      - "Harlem to Get Scottsboro Defense Group", Aug 30
      - "Fight Parties in Harlem", Aug 30
      - "Porters Plan March to Ask Wage Boost" [unverified], [Aug]
      - "Retail Clerks to Continue Picketing", Sep 2
      - "Harlem Plans Big Party Building Drive", Sep 2
      - "Harlem Women Hit Boost in Milk Price" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 3
      - "Negro Congress Directives are Issued", Sep 3
      - "Harlem to Denounce Terror in West Indies", Sep 4
      - "Insect-Ridden Medicine Given in Hospital" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 4
      - "African Leader Here to Discuss Home Issues", Sep 4
      - "2 Negro Women Attacked in IRT Subway" [unverified], Sep 5
      - "Negro Balting WPA Supervisor Out in the Cold" [unverified], Sep 5
      - "Mrs. Holmes and Daughters Drink from the Fountain of Communism" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 7
      - "Harlem Women Picket Milk Co. Tomorrow", Sep 8
      - "Harlem Rent Strike Ends; Tenants Win", Sep 8
      - "Amter to Open East Harlem Drive In Talk", Sep 9
      - "Harlem to Launch Fund Drive Tonight", Sep 9
      - "African Negro Under Martial Law, Says Head", Sep 9
      - "'Horseplay' at Lafayette Fun for Children and Grown-ups Alike" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 11
      - "Scores Picket Borden's Protesting High Milk Prices", Sep 11
      - "Lower Harlem Rally Spurs Party Drive", Sep 11
      - "Upper Harlem Rally to Hear Party History", Sep 11
      - "'Porters Have Closed Shop' --- Randolph", Sep 13
      - "Harlem Stores Sign CIO Union Pact", Sep 14
      - "East Harlem Party Building Drive Mapped", Sep 14
      - "24 Negro Families Begin Rent Strikes", Sep 16
      - "Scottsboro Rallies to be Held Tonight", Sep 17
      - "Scottsboro Drive Pushed", Sep 18
      - "Harlem Spanish Women Come Out of the Kitchen" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 20
      - "Scottsboro Mother Talks Monday Night", Sep 20
      - "East Harlem C.P. Recruits 40 Members", Sep 20
      - "Harlem Group Pushes Aid for China", Sep 22
      - "10,000 Negro Vets in N.Y. Silent, but They're Talking Up at Home" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 23
      - "Harlem C. P. to Open Educational Forum" [unverified], Sep 25
      - "Negro Pastor Assails Tokio Aggression", Sep 25
      - "Big Harlem Rally for China Tonight" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 27
      - "American Negroes in Key Posts of Spain's Loyalist Forces" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 29
      - "Randolph Urges Parley Between CIO-AFL Unions" [byline: Richard Wright], Sep 30
      - "Bates Tells of Spain's Fight For Strong Republican Army" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 1
      - "Amter Speaks at Harlem Rally Tonight" [unverified], Oct 2
      - "C. P. Nominee Withdraws to Aid A.L.P.", Oct 2
      - "Harlem Unions Back Nat'l. Negro Congress", Oct 4
      - "Scottsboro Drive Gains in Harlem", Oct 6
      - "Scottsboro Mother Sees Son in Jail", Oct 6
      - "Lower Harlem to Hear Amter Talk Tonight", Oct 7
      - "Opening of Harlem Project Homes Shows How Slums Can be Wiped Out in New York" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 8
      - "Socialists Back Negro Congress", Oct 8
      - "Mother, Three Children Are Evicted in Harlem", Oct 9
      - "Tim Holmes to Speak at Harlem Forum", Oct 9
      - "Heights Leads in Campaign for Press", Oct 11
      - "Hathaway and Amter Speak at Jewish Rally", Oct 11
      - "Negro Gets Job as City Buyer of All Chemicals", Oct 12
      - "Mrs. Roosevelt to Speak in Harlem Oct. 22", Oct 12
      - "Schedule Talk by Browder in Spanish Harlem", Oct 13
      - "She Lay Dying, But They Would Not Give Her Aid", Oct 13
      - "Harlem Plans Scottsboro Defense Rally", Oct 13
      - "Hotel Workers to Back Negro Conference", Oct 13
      - "See Biggest Negro Parley Since Days of Reconstruction" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 14
      - "Harlem Voters to Hear Amter Talk Saturday" [unverified], Oct 14
      - "National Negro Congress to Open Tomorrow in Philadelphia", Oct 14
      - "Scottsboro Meeting in Brooklyn Friday", Oct 14
      - "Negro Tradition in the Theatre" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 15
      - "Scottsboro Drive Backed by Candidate", Oct 15
      - "Public Libraries Need Books", Oct 15
      - "Harlem Rent Strike Gains New Supports" [unverified], Oct 17
      - "Negro Youth on March, Says Leader" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 7
      - "Harlem, Bronx Sign Competition Pact" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 19
      - "Harlem Rent Strikers Win in Court Fight", Oct 19
      - "Ford to Give Negro Congress Report Friday", Oct 19
      - "Harlem Negro Leaders Back Mayor for Liberal Views" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 20
      - "Juanita Hall to Sing", Oct 20
      - "Browder Talks in East Harlem", Oct 21
      - "Ask Aid for Scottsboro Defense Drive", Oct 21
      - "Browder to Speak in Harlem Tomorrow" [unverified], Oct 21
      - "Patterson Talks Friday in Harlem", Oct 21
      - "YCL Supports Harlem C.P. Daily Drive", Oct 21
      - "Browder Warns of Growth of Fascism in Latin Americas" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 23
      - "Ford, in Harlem Talk, Lauds Negro Congress" [unverified], Oct 24
      - "New Negro Pamphlet Stresses Need for U.S. People's Front" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 25
      - "Scottsboro Parley in Harlem Tonight", Oct 25
      - "100 Women to Score Gijon Massacre", Oct 26
      - "Harlem Women to Get Advice on Meat Buying", Oct 26
      - "Parley Maps Scottsboro Campaign", Oct 26
      - "Mayor Gets Backing of Porters" [unverified], Oct 27
      - "LaGuardia, Dewey to Speak in Harlem Friday" [unverified], Oct 28
      - "Lecture on P.R. Sunday at People's Forum" [unverified], Oct 28
      - "Scottsboro Drive Pushed by Harlem C.P.", Oct 29
      - "Fifty Fascists Attack Women's Picket Line", Oct 30
      - "Harlem Leaders Rap Amsterdam News' Stand for Mahoney" [byline: Richard Wright], Oct 30
      - "Mayor Signs Scottsboro Petition" [unverified], Oct 31
      - "Mayor to Make Final Talk on 'Lucky Corner'" [unverified], Nov 1
      - "Plan to Push Scottsboro Campaign", Nov 1
      - "Picket Lines Win Withdrawal of All Goods Made in Japan", Nov 1
      - "Harlem Vote Swings Away from Tiger" [byline: Richard Wright], Nov 2
      - "Negro Leaders Hail Victory of A.L.P. at New York Polls" [byline: Richard Wright], Nov 2
      - "Stachel to Speak Friday in Harlem", Nov 5
      - "Negro School Boy Attacked by Teacher", Nov 5
      - "Harlem Concert to Mark Soviet Union Festival", Nov 6
      - "Plan to Aid Negroes in West Indies", Nov 6
      - "Tenants Plan Big League in Harlem", Nov 6
      - "A.L.P. Assemblyman Urges State Control of Price of Milk" [byline: Richard Wright], Nov 8
      - "Scottsboro Mother to Lead Protest", Nov 8
      - "Stachel Sounds Call for Unity of Unions in Harlem Address", Nov 8
      - "Tenants Push Fight on High Harlem Rents" [unverified], Nov 8
      - "Sharecropper Friends to Hold Savoy Dance", Nov 9
      - "Harlem Rally to Protest Milk Gouge" [unverified], Nov 11
      - "Negroes Form Committee to Aid Spain", Nov 12
      - "Call Parley to Aid West Indian Negroes", Nov 12
      - "Negro Social Worker Hails Housing, Education in Spain" [byline: Richard Wright], Nov 12
      - "Scottsboro Sunday Tomorrow in New York Baptist Churches", Nov 13
      - "Tenants Win Compromise in Harlem Fight" [unverified], Nov 13
      - "Scottsboro Drive Backed by State C.P.", Nov 15
      - "Negroes Win Back Jobs on WPA Theatre", Nov 15
      - "Scottsboro Mother to Lead Delegation", Nov 15
      - "Patterson Speaks on USSR Nov. 18 at Harlem Forum", Nov 16
      - "Scottsboro Delegation is Chosen", Nov 17
      - "Harlem Rent Strikers Win Agreement", Nov 17
      - "ALP Assemblyman in Harlem Hails Unity of Labor at Polls" [byline: Richard Wright], Nov 18
      - "Anti-Lynching Delegation Delays Trip", Nov 18
      - "Baby Carriage Parade to Protest Milk Gouge", Nov 20
      - "Harlem Leaders Hit Tory Filibuster on Anti-Lynch Bill", Nov 20
      - "Rep. O'Connell Urges Democracies to Unite in Fight on Fascism", Nov 22
      - "YCL Session Opens Nov. 26 in Brooklyn", Nov 22
      - "Memorial for Milton Herndon Next Sunday", Nov 22
      - "Negro Tenants Win Rent Cuts in 8 Houses" [unverified], Nov 23
      - "2 Scottsboro Boys Leave on National Tour", Nov 24
      - "Ford Replies to Negro Pastor in Discussion of Fascist Peril", Nov 26
      - "Honor Herndon at Harlem Rally Sunday", Nov 27
      - "Negro Congressman to Speak Sunday in Harlem Church", Nov 27
      - "Few Harlem Tables Weighted by Turkey", Nov 29
      - "Herndon is Honored at Memorial" [unverified], Nov 29
      - "Walter Garland Tells What Spain's Fight Against Fascism Means to the Negro People" [byline: Richard Wright], Nov 29
      - "Harlem ALP to Launch Social Welfare Program" [unverified], Nov 30
      - "Pickets Force Stores to Ban Japanese Goods", Nov 30
      - "Boycott is Spreading in Harlem's Stores", Dec 2
      - "Assemblyman From Harlem to Map Plans", Dec 4
      - "Weisbecker Strike Strong in Harlem", Dec 4
      - "Harlem, East Side Honor Hero Who Died in Rescue of Negroes" [byline: Richard Wright], Dec 6
      - "'He Died by Them'- Hero's Widow Tells of Rescue of Negroes" [byline: Richard Wright], Dec 6
      - "YCL Pushes Scottsboro Defense Fight", Dec 6
      - "Harlem Pays Tribute to Truckdriver Who Rescued Negro Children in Fire", Dec 8
      - "Scottsboro Group Warns on T. S. Harten", Dec 8
      - "12 Harlem Shops Sign to Ban Fascist Goods", Dec 9
      - "Probe of Negro Conditions Opens December 13", Dec 9
      - "Hearings Monday in Harlem on Negro Conditions [unverified], Dec 13
      - "Huge Negro Death Rate Shown in Niagara Frontier Studies", Dec 13
      - "Ban on Negro Doctors Bared at City Probe" [byline: Richard Wright], Dec 14
      - "Sen. Barkley Warns U.S. of War Makers", Dec 14
      - "Red Caps to Meet Jan. 14 in Chicago", Dec 14
      - "Ban on Negro Doctors Bares at City Probe" [unverified], Dec 15
      - "Gouging, Landlord Discrimination against Negroes Bared at Hearing" [byline: Richard Wright], Dec 15
      - "2 Cops Slay Negro Youth", Dec 16
      - "Utilities Admit Bars to Negro on Jobs", Dec 16
      - "Plan Memorial For Heroic Truck Driver", Dec 18
      - "300 at Harlem ERB Sit in to Demand Rent, Food Budgets", Dec 18
      - "Berry to Lead Forum in Congress Discussion", Dec 18
      - "Pickets Ask Somervell Ouster for Negro Firings", Dec 21
      - "From Spain's Loyalist Trenches Larry Foy Asks About Harlem's Fight Against Fascism in the U.S.", Dec 23